Guide to the Stephen Harty papers, 1992-2001 and undated
The John W. Hartman Center for Sales, Advertising & Marketing History David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library Duke University Durham, N.C., USA
Stephen Harty papers 1992-2001 and undated
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library, Duke University
Harty, Stephen
1.2 Linear Feet Linear Feet 750 Items Items
Stephen Harty is an advertising executive who began his career at Ogilvy & Mather and later became North American Chairman of Bartle Bogle Hegarty agency. Harty co-founded Merkley Newman Harty advertising agency (later renamed Merkley+Partners), part of the Omnicom Group.
The Stephen Harty Papers cover the years 1992-2001, and contains primarily files relating to the founding of Merkley Newman Harty (MNH) advertising agency. Records consist of notes on strategic plans; annual meetings; agency founding; articles featuring MNH; promotional booklets; clippings; photographs and proofs of print advertiesements that chronicle the purpose, history, philosophy, and goals of MNH. Clients mentioned in materials include The American Stock Exchange, Bankers Trust, BellSouth, Casio (Kashio), Champion Sportswear (Hanes), Dime Bank, Forbes, General Electric, IBM, International Wool Secretariat, M&M/Mars, Oxford Health Plan, TDK, Time Life Medical, Volvic Natural Spring Water, and WordPerfect. Acquired as part of the John W. Hartman Center for Sales, Advertising & Marketing History.
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
Collection is open for research.
Researchers must register and agree to copyright and privacy laws before using this collection.
All or portions of this collection may be housed off-site in Duke University's Library Service Center. The library may require up to 48 hours to retrieve these materials for research use.
Please contact Research Services staff before visiting the David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library to use this collection.
Provenance
The Stephen Harty papers were received by the David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library as a gift in 2007.
Biographical Note
Chronology List
1952 Born, New Jersey
1973 BA, Williams College
1973-1978 Managed non-profit theater, New York, New York
circa 1973 Municipal Labor Force Analyist, Office of Operations with Mayor Ed Koch, New York, New York
circa 1978-1980 MA, Yale School of Management
circa 1980-92 Account Manager, Ogilvy & Mather
1983 White House Fellow, Washington, D.C.; Special Assistant to William Webster, Director of FBI
1992 Co-founded Merkley Newman Harty with Parry Merkley and Jane Newman, in New York, N.Y.
1992-2001 Director of Client Services, Merkley Newman Harty
2006 Chairman, Bartle Bogle Hegarty, North America
Harty served as chairman of the Williams College and Yale SOM Alumni Funds; Board member for Williamstown Theatre Festival, The New Dramatists, and Photographers & Friends Against AIDS; and President of the Society of Alumni of Williams College.
Collection Overview
The Stephen Harty Papers cover the years 1992-2001, and contains primarily files relating to the founding of Merkley Newman Harty (MNH) advertising agency. Records consist of notes on strategic plans; annual meetings; agency founding; articles featuring MNH; promotional booklets; clippings; photographs and proofs of print advertisements that chronicle the purpose, history, philosophy, and goals of MNH. Clients mentioned in materials include The American Stock Exchange, Bankers Trust, BellSouth, Casio (Kashio), Champion Sportswear (Hanes), Dime Bank, Forbes, General Electric, IBM, International Wool Secretariat, M&M/Mars, Oxford Health Plan, TDK, Time Life Medical, Volvic Natural Spring Water, and WordPerfect.
Subject Headings
These are searchable subject entries for this collection. Performing a search on these subjects in the Duke University Libraries online catalog will bring up other related research materials.
Harty, Stephen
Ogilvy & Mather
American Stock Exchange
Bankers Trust Company (New York, N.Y.)
BellSouth Corporation
Forbes Inc
General Electric Company
Hanes Menswear, Inc
International Business Machines Corporation
International Wool Secretariat
Kashio Keisanki Kabushiki Kaisha
TDK Kabushiki Kaisha
Time Life Medical
Volvic (France)
WordPerfect Corporation
Advertising agencies
Advertising agencies -- United States -- History
Advertising executives
Advertising executives -- United States
Marketing -- United States
Photographs
Tear sheets
John W. Hartman Center for Sales, Advertising & Marketing History
- General Files 1992-2001 and undated, (3 boxes)
  Includes notes on strategic plans, annual meetings, agency founding, articles featuring MHH, promotional booklets, clippings, photographs and proofs that chronicle the purpose, history, philosophy, and goals of MNH. Arranged alphabetically.
  - Agency Day/follow up, 1993 (Box 1)
  - Agency general meeting, 1994-2000
  - Agency launch
  - Agency meeting, 1994
  - Agency Raison D'Etre
  - Newspaper clippings, 1993-1995, 1999, (2 folders) (Box 2)
  - Offsite staff development meeting, Brodeur & Associates, 1994
  - Organizational charts
  - Press
  - [Proof, print advertisement for IBM, 1994: Removed to Oversize Materials, Box 4]
  - Publications
    - Foote, Cone & Belding Worldwide, undated
    - Merkley Newman Harty, undated, (3 folders)
    - [Merkley Newman Harty, The first 100 days, 1993: Removed to Oversize Materials, Box 4]
    - What we want to be when we grow up, undated
  - Staff meeting, 1992 (Box 3)
  - Strategic plan, 1998-2001, (5 folders)
- Oversize Materials, (1 box)
  - IBM proof print advertisement, 1994 (Box 4)
  - Publication, The first 100 days, 1993